Good morning, Canvas. It's a pleasure to be with you guys again. I know I said a version
of this last time I was here, and I promise it's not like me sucking up to the hose, but
I really love coming here. Like, I mean, you guys know a little bit of our story. You
know, the church that I was pastoring in D.C., we had to close it. I mean, they're traveling
to different churches and speaking, so we haven't really found a home. And I'll be
honest, partially because of how often I'm coming, but the closest thing to, like, a home
church that we have right now, at least for me, it's you guys. So I'm really, really happy
to be here right now. With that, I think I'm going to be here, like, the next three weeks
in a row, doing, like, a little bit of preacher wrestling. So yeah, we'll see more of each
other in the next few weeks. And that's my sermon for today. Thank you very much. Is that short
enough, man? Like, does that work for us from what you want to do? No, no, no. We're doing
this series on the fruit of the Spirit. And, you know, this list of nine character traits,
we're going to try to explain to somebody, what does it mean to look like Jesus? What
the Bible is coming back to is this not really simple, looking like Jesus looks like the
evidence of this fruit in your life. And today we're exploring the third fruit of this passage
in Galatians 5.22 that says, for the fruit of the Spirit, and he goes to say love, joy,
and today we get to the fruit of peace. When you hear the word peace, what's the first
thing that comes to your mind? I want to be honest with you guys, the first thing that
comes to my mind is a scene from the classic American song about patriotism and freedom,
Independence Day. All right? And there's a scene in Independence Day that one of the aliens
is kind of like the control of the scientists and he's speaking to the alien. And, you know,
the greatest, I think, like, fake president we've had, Bill Pullman, is talking to the alien and
he's like, you know, like, we have peace. And the alien is like, peace. No, peace.
Listen, I watch a movie every 4th of July. Like, that's my tradition. Like, we wake up and have
breakfast and then I watch America, like, you know, kicking some alien rears and it's great.
Like, I'm ready for fireworks after that. But anyway, that's just me. I'm weird. I know.
Like, that's what I think of when I think about things. But what do you think? Like,
if you hear the word peace, what's the first thing that comes to our mind? I think about,
you know, that scene when he's in no peace. And if we're honest for a second, that's kind
of like the world that it feels like we're living in right now, right? I remember reading
some reports about the aftermath of everything that happened in the last couple of years and
kind of like the CDC and a couple of stories and what the effect that had on people's mental
health, right? And there were things, for example, like, you know, the people that were
being treated for anxiety and depression, like, jumps, you know, there's something like
36% goes to, like, 40%, you know, people that needed increased care in mental health, that
jumped. The APL had done a poll last year. And basically, in 2021, you had 40% more Americans
that were more anxious than had been before from the prior year, which actually was an improvement
because in 2020, you wonder what happened that year. Like, that number had jumped 60%.
You know, 53% of parents are concerned about the mental health of their children. 43% of
adults report that, you know, the pandemic had a serious impact on their mental health. Not
to mention that right now, like, you know, in the mix of everything that's going on, like,
there's a war going on on the other side of the world. That it's a funny line, right?
But it would seem that the world around us is kind of like saying that, right? There is no peace right now.
Which is what makes the passage that we read this morning, both good news, but somehow it seems that
one of the evidence, one of the fruit of the Holy Spirit in our lives is peace. But at the same time,
it makes it a little bit confusing. Because it seems like peace is one of those things that's almost
impossible to achieve right now. And one of the things you're going to notice as we're going through this
through the Spirit, is that a lot of the words that we're reading, you know, love, joy, peace,
these are things that we have some level of concept, even if you're not a Christian, right? Like, if you're
asking somebody that's not a Christian, have you experienced love? Have you experienced joy? Have you experienced peace?
They would say yes to a certain degree, right? And that begs the question, well, what's so special about
Christianity? What's so special about the Holy Spirit that's saying that these fruits are only
evidence of the presence of the Holy Spirit in your life? And what you're going to start noticing
is that what the writers of the New Testament do is that they take these words, they take these terms
that kind of like we're all familiar with, and they sort of redefine them, right? Because you remember
when we were talking about love, how we have this conception of love, and basically, Christianity,
like, basically almost had to, like, invent the word, like this agape word that meant something
completely different for Greek people, to even begin to explain what they were talking about when
they were talking about love, because it was such an outlandish concept for that period of time.
And I think that with peace today that we're looking at, it's sort of like the same deal.
If I were to ask you, you know, what you understand by peace, you probably would mention one of two
things. One is that you think about peace as the other conflict, right? Like, if we're not a war,
we're at peace. That might be between nations, or between people groups, or, you know, between you
and some interpersonal conflict with another person. Or maybe you would think about it in more personal
terms that, you know, we use the term inner peace a lot of times. And we think about, like,
it's almost like this sense of, like, calmness and tranquility and, you know, the absence of inner turmoil
or of anxieties. External peace is the opposite of conflict with others. Inner peace is kind of like the
opposite of inner conflict. And I think, actually, what the Apostle Paul is referring to in this passage is
that second understanding of inner peace. Now, the issue is, as I was telling you, that inner peace is
actually a thing that seems very, very, very hard to address. Think about all these statistics that we're
reading about, the increase of, you know, anxiety and depression and mental health issues in general.
And what those, what I think those numbers point to is that this idea of inner peace is actually not so
inner, right? That it would seem that we live in a world where there are so many things that are happening
on the outside that affect our internal life and affect our mental health and that diminish our sense of inner peace.
Think about the rise of the wellness industry, right? From medication apps to retreat to, like,
CBD products. Like, I think I've shared with you guys a little bit how, like, you know,
I've been sharing a little bit with anxiety and depression and the aftermath of the closing of our church.
And, you know, I don't know how Mark Zuckerberg found out, but, like, my Instagram feed is just
like a bunch of ads about, like, all these different wellness apps that I should give a try.
I looked at this. The global wellness industry right now is valued at $4.2 trillion. It has risen
as fast as, twice as fast as the rest of the global economy. Which is funny because a few years ago,
it was kind of like a fringe thing, right? And I think there's a number of reasons for that,
but one of the reasons I would argue is that the factors that affect our mental health and
increase our anxiety, as these factors rise in the world, so do our attempts to combat those factors
in search of inner peace. Now, listen, I'm not coming out as, like, against the whole wellness
industry or whatever, like, you know, we should be, you know, careful with some stuff. Some of those
things help me, like, you know, like, talking to a therapist is great and, like, you know, I've been
benefiting from that. But what I'm saying is that when it comes to these ideas of inner peace,
I think it's pretty evident that we have a problem as a society, you know? And part of that problem
is that so many of the things that drive our anxiety and our inner turmoil are things that are outside
of our control. I remember I see yourself listening to this sermon by a pastor in Portland named John
Mark Comer, and he was saying that he referenced this statistic. I've no idea where he got it from,
so he could be making this up because pastors do that sometimes. I don't know, right? But he said
the statistic that we only have control over about 15 percent of the things that happen in our life,
which sounds insane until you realize that, you know, half the time when your boss is a bad
man has nothing to do with you. Maybe he had a fat guy that morning or had a fat with his wife,
and I'll go in your day for that, and you have nothing to do with it, right? So, like, it's actually
something that rings true. And if we have so little control over the things that cause our anxiety,
anxiety, you know, whatever techniques, whatever meditation apps, whatever, you know, wellness
attempts that we try to do are only going to help us cope so far with anxiety and our inner turmoil.
And so, like, it's not bad things, but it would seem that for the Apostle Paul, there is a peace that's beyond that that can be achieved.
I still think part of the problem is that we spend all this time kind of, like, trying to chase and trying to balance
everything around us in order to achieve peace. And most of the time what it feels that we can have it for specific moments, right?
Like, there's like a half hour between the time that your paycheck hits your bank account and your bills start coming out and everything looks great.
And then, like, that car payment comes out and you're like, oh my, no, no, no, no, no, if you want me to know, right?
Like, there's this moment where, like, the kids go to bed and it's like you clean the kitchen and you sit down and, oh, everything is great, right?
And then you remember that you still have laundry that you have to take care of.
Like, we have these moments that we're chasing after and we feel like we can grasp peace for a few minutes and then he sort of, like, just walks around.
And for the writers of the Bible, though, peace and the fruit of the Spirit is a completely different thing.
I want to show you that.
So, I want to take you to a passage in the Gospel of John.
We're going to be in John chapter 14.
And this is an interesting passage.
The Gospel of John kind of, like, frames the Last Supper that Jesus has with his disciples
with all of these, like, long discourses and conversations that Jesus gives probably more than any other writer in the Scriptures.
It's basically, like, Jesus is, like, he's going to get arrested and he's kind of, like, trying to do, like, a download of information on his disciples
and everything that they need to know before he gets arrested.
So, we pick up, kind of, like, at the end of that scene, they finish having dinner, and this is what Jesus said.
This is John chapter 14, verse 25.
All these I have spoken was so with you.
But the Advocate, the Holy Spirit, whom the Father will send in my name, will teach you all things and will remind you of everything I have said to you.
So, it's kind of like giving the disciples final instruction.
He's basically telling them, hey, listen, I'm not going to be around in this physical, fleshly form that you see me all the time.
And then he's kind of, like, hinting at this idea that somebody's going to come after him.
And he's just this different name, like, the Advocate of the Holy Spirit.
Now, what I want you to see is what happens after that.
So, verse 27, this is this.
So, he's talking about the Holy Spirit.
And then he says,
Peace I lift west to you.
My peace I give you.
And I do not give it to you as the world gives.
Do not let your hearts be troubled.
And do not be afraid.
So, Jesus is kind of, like, downloading all this information, giving all these different commands, giving all these final instructions.
And then he reiterates his promise that he's given before that he's going to send his helper, the Holy Spirit.
And then, if you keep reading, it's almost like he makes this completely abrupt change that, you know, he goes from talking about the Holy Spirit to talking about peace.
And if you're reading it, kind of, like, with all kinds of things, like, what's going on here?
Now, let's keep reading and see how he kind of, like, goes back and forth in this conversation.
So, verse 28.
You heard me say, I am going away, and I am coming back to you.
If you love me, you would be glad that I am going to the Father, for the Father is greater than I.
I have told you now before it happens, so that when it does happen, you will believe.
I will not say much more to you, for the Prince of this world is coming.
He has no hold over me, but he comes to that the world may learn that I love the Father and do exactly what my Father has commanded me.
Come now, let us leave.
So, if you're kind of like, if we're to, like, break down this passage, it's like a very spatter-brained passage.
You're talking to his disciples, like, listen, I'm going to get arrested, I'm going to leave, but the Holy Spirit is going to come.
And then he goes to say, hey, by the way, I'm going to leave you my, I'm going to leave my peace with you.
And then again, he's like, and I'm going to leave.
If you should really be start passing, on the surface of the conversation, it would seem kind of like this very confusing thing that he's talking about.
I mean, you're really, you know, what does peace have to do with any, I mean, obviously when it's a case in descriptors, there's a lot more going on, probably right on the surface when you start digging on it.
The first thing is this, when you hear the word peace used in a context of, like, you know, a departure or an arrival, peace at that point in most cultures was sort of like the fundamental greeting and farewell salutation.
People didn't say hello, people say goodbye, people say peace, right?
Now, you still do that, like you said, peace out, right?
Where you're wishing people peace, like that's where this comes from, believing or not.
So, in that sense, when you're reading the passage, Jesus is saying that he's leaving his peace, but right after the fact, he's talking about that he's going to actually leave.
It's almost like the writers are kind of like trying to say, Jesus is saying goodbye, and I say goodbye, the formal thing that you do is that you wish somebody peace.
He's just connecting this idea of this common greeting that you had at the time, but he uses this to like do like a much deeper message, right?
Like on the surface, he's like, I'm leaving soon, peace out.
But at the same time, he's taking that phrase and kind of like starting to expand a little bit on peace is the fruit of the Spirit.
What I'm saying, he says, peace I live with you, my peace I give you, I do not give to you as the world gives.
Part of what he's saying is you're going to like paraphrase that whole passage.
He's like, you know how, you know, when people say goodbye to you and say hello to you, they wish you peace.
Then he's like saying, it's a nice gentleman, but that's all it is.
It's wishful thinking.
It might not be sincere, but they cannot actually give you peace.
It's what he's saying, I'm not giving to you like the world gives.
And then he says, well, I'm going to leave, and because I'm going to leave, I'm also going to say, please, but this is different.
I'm not only going to wish you peace, I'm actually going to give you peace.
I'm actually going to leave my peace with you.
Like when you read that passage and you're reading a language, the Greek grammar is very possessive.
He's basically saying, if you were to say, literally, he says, the peace that is mine, I'm giving to you.
What he's saying is the world cannot give you the type of peace that I'm talking about because this peace only belongs to me.
Which is interesting because I think that it resonates with what we've been talking about because what Jesus is getting out is this.
When he says, you know, like, you know, I don't give you the peace that the world gives.
I think he's getting to this idea that peace in the world, when you think about it, like peace for the world, it usually means favorable circumstances.
But when we think about when would you have peace, you will probably start going through a mental list of the things that would have to be in order and under your control to feel that peace.
You will want to have X amount of money in your savings.
You will have to, you will want to make sure that, like, when you are, you know, whatever you're bringing in covers all of your expenses.
You will want to make sure that all of your relationships are in order.
There's nothing unexpected.
You might not think about it like that, but if I was to, as you describe the perfect peaceful circumstance,
it would mean something like all of the circumstances outside of me are sort of, like, under my control,
and I don't have to worry about them.
So many of the ways in which we are trying to achieve inner peace is the pursuit of that.
There's plenty of people that, like, work really hard and worry about money a lot,
not because they're greedy, but because they're desperate to find peace.
And they're saying, if I just get to this number, if I just get to making this match,
if I just get to hitting this number in life, I'm going to have peace.
The people that have dreams that pursue, not necessarily because of just some selfish ambition about that dream,
but it's like, you know, if I buy a house and I don't have to rent, well, then maybe I will have peace.
If I can send out my kids for success in these days, if I can send them to these schools.
You know what I'm saying?
Like, we think about peace as a result of favorable circumstances.
And the problem is that, as we were reading, so often we have very little control over the circumstances.
If we learn anything the last three years now, good luck.
If we learn anything about the last three years, it's that we have so very little control about what's going on.
Or the other thing that we try to do is that we try to treat the symptoms of that.
Like, I experienced that a lot when I started suffering of anxiety attacks.
Because some of the things that, but my problem is, you know, candy with you for a second,
is that my mind always goes to, like, the worst case scenario, right?
So, if something happens, it's not like, you know, like, thinking about the church, for example, right?
Like, we had to shut down the church for me.
It's not like, oh, man, like, we shut down the church and we have to, like, have to find a new job or whatever.
No, it's like, I'm never going to find a job.
This is kind of, like, going to be this dark cloud that hangs over me.
I'm not going into poverty.
My wife is going to leave me.
My kids are going to talk to me.
Like, my mind goes immediately to, like, the worst version of whatever the thing is.
So, what's that mean with my set up is, like, listen, A, most of this stuff you're making up.
Like, it's not, this is, like, ridiculous.
But for your brain, it's true.
And he says, but B, even if that was going to happen, there's an incredible little control that you have out right now.
So, like, a lot of what we work through is exercise system, ways of trying to, like, you know,
clearing my mind and calming myself and, like, you know, calming down from anxiety attacks.
And that's an incredibly awesome.
So, now, this is, like, what that is doing, which is necessary, is helping me treat the symptoms of my lack of peace.
It's equivalent, I don't know, when you get a cold, I don't know what, like, your medicine or choice is.
For me, it's, like, seraflu, like, the little package that you put in, like, hot water and drink.
Like, that's the only thing that I can, like, I can, like, when I have a cold, like, my face is congested.
That's the only thing that allows me to, like, sleep.
Like, I need to take that and that clear to me, like, I feel good enough that I can actually pull a sleep.
And for the longest time, I remember thinking that that was, like, cold medicine, right?
And then, I don't know if I was talking with my wife or with a friend of the doctor,
but somebody explained to me that seraflu is actually not cold medicine.
What seraflu is doing is, like, helping calm the symptoms so that you can survive and make it through the day.
But it's actually doing nothing to fight whatever infection is going on.
It's actually doing nothing to fight.
Like, that's, like, if you have a virus, you have to wait for that virus to kind of, like, make its way through your body.
And so many of, like, the apps that we use, the techniques that we use, they're necessary.
They're important.
Why?
Because if you have an anxiety attack, your kid still needs to get fed, right?
And, like, you still need to go to work.
So, you have to deal with that.
So, it has a place.
It's important.
But it's really only treating the symptom.
It's not getting at the root cause of the issue.
So, Jesus comes in, and he completely upends the disciples' understanding of peace,
because he starts talking about peace, and he mentions nothing about external circumstances, right?
He says something interesting.
He says, do not let your hearts be troubled.
It would seem to imply that maybe a thing that disturbs our peace fundamentally is not our external circumstances,
but our hearts, our inner life.
Now, what's interesting, though, is that Jesus has answered and doesn't seem to be, hey, if you can just calm your mind and calm your brain and distract yourself from all these things that are worrying you,
you are going to experience peace.
He actually gets, kind of like, makes a very challenging statement to make.
Like, he's saying, like, actually, you cannot find true peace on your own.
You need a peace that can only come from me.
Now, what's even more incredible is that then he says, but, but, if you get this peace, you are going to be able to face anything that comes your way.
So, he says, do not let your hearts be troubled.
And that's basically, he's talking about anxiety.
And do not be afraid.
The implication of this is time, because he's basically saying the fruit of the Spirit of peace in your life kind of allows us to experience peace and face anxiety regardless of what our external circumstances are.
All right, the best way I can explain this to you is this.
Without Jesus, the best we can hope for is to cope with the world around us, to get enough to bear and survive.
And that's important.
Like, I want to make sure I'm saying this, because I'm the guy, like, I take medication, and I do a lot of things to kind of, like, you know, work on those external things.
Like, no, it's within me that that is not the ultimate solution that's helping me cope.
Jesus is not offering to help you cope.
Jesus is not doing something incredibly more profound.
He's actually offering to help you transcend.
The peace in Christ is not a peace that copes with circumstances.
Peace in Christ is a peace that transcends circumstances.
Okay?
Now, what's important about it is, what this is saying, it's kind of like getting a very core, you know, issue here,
is that, what he's saying is that so much of our frustrations with God,
so many of, like, the times of prayer where we're desperate and heartbroken and crying out to God,
most of them are usually asking for him to change circumstances.
Right?
Most of them are, hey, God, like, this is going on in my life, and I don't know what to do about it,
and I need you to tell me.
And listen, I'm not preaching against, not preaching for the disease.
You should preach, pray for the disease.
You should hope for the disease.
We've talked about this before, but it's almost like you're saying, listen,
what if you could step that bit over?
What if you could experience peace not when, you know, the job comes,
and the bank account looks good, and, you know, the promotion happens,
and, like, the relationship kills?
What if you could experience peace now, in the midst of that,
regardless of what's happening?
Again, I just want to say for them, because, like, the way the world works,
a lot of the things that we're hoping to kind of, like, come into place for peace to happen,
they take time, right?
But, like, if you're saying, hey, I'm only going to experience peace when, you know,
my bank account is this number, and, like, your number is down here,
it might take you a few months, a few years to get there, right?
And the question that you're asking is, do you want to spend, are you asking me to, like,
magically wave a brand and, like, just make the money up your bank account?
Or, like, are you going to wait all that time?
And then the question is, do you want to wait all that time without peace?
What is the relationship passing now?
What if you cannot force the other person to forgive you?
And what you're saying is that in the midst of everything that's happened, whatever,
you know, however crazy the world might look, like, you can experience peace right now.
The peace that I'm offering to you is a peace that transcends circumstances.
Now, I'm going to skip a bunch of stuff to kind of, like, keep it in 30 minutes.
Don't worry, I'm picking on you, but if you want to know the rest, we can talk later.
I want to take you to a passage in the book of Philippians,
and we're kind of, like, close with this, Philippians chapter 4, verse 4.
And what I want to show you is kind of, like, the Bible actually gives sort of, like, a road map of how do we access this?
Because everything that I've told you is great.
I'm the person to say, like, a month and a half ago, I was suffering anxiety attacks every day.
Okay?
And I knew this stuff then.
I've written this down on me for it.
So I knew this stuff then.
At that moment, it wasn't making that much of a difference, right?
Because there's moments in my life where you can know this.
Okay, so how do I access this?
One of the things that we see is that it's a product of the Holy Spirit.
So it's a product of our dwelling with the Holy Spirit.
But what does that look like when it comes to peace?
And I think that this passage actually gives us a roadmap for this.
This is Philippians chapter 4.
I'm just reading in verse 4.
Rejoice in the Lord always.
I will say it again.
Rejoice.
Let your gentleness be evident to all.
The Lord is near.
Do not be anxious about anything.
But in every situation, by prayer and petition with thanksgiving, present your request to God.
And the peace of God, which presents all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.
Finally, brothers and sisters, whatever is true, whatever is noble, whatever is right, whatever is pure, whatever is lovely, whatever is admirable.
If anything is excellent or praiseworthy, think about such things.
Whatever you have learned or received or heard from me or seen me, put it into practice and the God of peace will be with you.
Now, my question about this passage is that Paul is running this to jail.
Like, Paul is in prison awaiting to be judged.
And he's the one that writes to people, say, rejoice.
And experience peace and let go of anxiety.
So, the guy actually, you know, A, has some sort of secret about it.
But also, it would seem that you can rejoice and experience peace even if you're in jail, right?
And that's a normal concept to me.
Because I don't think that if I was in jail, I was experiencing that much pain.
But I think that in this passage, actually, this road map, and I want to show you how to start, you know, the passage.
He says, you know, now, to my brothers and sisters, rejoice that you have not been able to all.
Verse 6, do not be anxious about anything but in every situation by prayer and petition.
So, the first thing that he's talking about is how we react to our circumstances.
What I'm saying is that the way you react to your circumstances, you kind of, like, redirect whatever circumstances is to God.
And that's why I'm saying that we don't have to stop praying.
Because apparently for Paul, it's, well, that's actually the first thing that you do.
With prayer and petition, you come before that.
So, whatever happens, don't just dwell on it.
Don't just kind of, like, let that simmer.
Don't, like, let your mind.
Like, what happens to me, like, my mind goes on these deep, dark robbing holes of, like, the worst-case scenario.
Paul is saying, no, no, no, the first thing you do is you bring it to God.
To the first thing.
But then, he comes in, like, says, with thanksgiving.
So, he's saying, when you, and this is a guy, this is a guy in jail.
And this is not only a guy in jail.
This is a guy in jail for serving God.
This is not a guy in jail that, like, he stole taxes and that's when he ended up in jail.
Or, like, you know, had a DUI.
This is a guy that was thrown to jail for serving God.
If anybody can, like, be better towards God and complaining to God about why is this happening to me as him.
And he's saying, no, no, actually, even in my circumstance, I direct whatever is going on towards God.
But then, my attitude, and I hate, like, the rhyming thing, but my attitude is gratitude.
And I'm very good.
Like, it's a difficult fashion thing.
He's saying, like, you have to do it with a spirit of saying, excuse me.
So, how we react to some prayer, then what our attitude is should be gratitude.
And then, if you kind of get towards the end of the situation, whatever is, and then he's saying, lovely, pure, beautiful.
What's he talking about?
What he's talking about is what we focus on.
So, in the midst of whatever circumstances, you can focus on everything that could go wrong.
Or you could focus on how you've already seen God in your life.
For me, the last few months, you know what that has been?
It's been my family.
Like, my family has been this evidence of God's goodness.
Like, I had this dream.
All I wanted to do was to be a pastor.
All I wanted to do was, like, to be a church planter in the city.
That was kind of like my dream.
And when that dream went away, part of what was happening internally was, like, well, what do I do with my life now?
Right?
And what I realized that God showed me in that place was, like, I would trade that a thousand times over for my wife, man, and my son, Jack.
And the simple but incredibly deep and profound joy of being with them.
And the most I focused on that, the more that I started experiencing peace and joy and happiness.
So, it would seem that the Apostle Paul would say, hey, when the problems come your way, react to prayer.
And maintain this attitude of thanksgiving and gratitude.
And focus on the good.
Focus on the things that God is already doing.
And I said, something happens when we do that.
When there's this mixture of, like, if you think about the two elements that it's like a sandwich, like prayer and what we focus on, it's God.
We're, like, directing our hearts to God and we're focusing on the goodness of God.
And in the middle of that, kind of, like, if we can thank God for what He's doing us, somehow that's where the Holy Spirit makes our lives.
And we can experience the peace of God.
I don't know if you guys are familiar with the song, It Is Well With My Soul, the hymn.
Do you know the story of how that hymn was written?
So, that hymn is written in the kind of, like, late 1800s.
The guy that wrote that hymn is a guy named Horatius Paffert.
Horatius Paffert is kind of like this famous lawyer in Chicago.
He has, like, this big real estate business.
And when Chicago fires happened in, like, 1831, he loses everything that he has.
He loses everything that he has.
There's this kind of, like, at that point, there was, like, this wave of sickness.
He has, like, five kids and loses a four-year-old son to, like, Scarlet View.
And, you know, in the aftermath of that, he starts rebuilding this business.
And a couple years after that, he feels that what his family needs is a vacation.
So, they plan a trip.
And at that point, it was, like, a trip on a ship.
So, like, you have to, like, you know, it takes weeks to get to Europe.
So, at the last minute of that trip, he has something come up with his business.
So, he has to stay behind for a few days.
So, he sends his wife and his four daughters on the ship, and he stays behind.
That ship hits another ship on the way to Europe, and the ship sinks.
And most everybody dies.
Somehow, his wife is rescued by a boat, but his daughters die.
And when his wife finally makes it to shore, she sends a telegram.
And all the telegram says to her husband, he's saved, alone, what shall I do?
When her husband gets a telegram, he gets on the first boat that he can, and he's on his way to see his wife.
And because this, you know, event had become famous and had caused this commotion,
when they're going towards a certain point on the journey, the captain calls her husband to his quarters.
And he says, hey, just so you know, what we're going through right now on the ship, this is where the crash happened.
And on the aftermath of that, on the ship, on his way to see his wife, that's all he has left.
He writes,
When peace, like a river, attendeth my way.
When sorrows, like sea billows, roll.
Whatever, my Lord, thou hast told me to say, it is well.
It is well with my soul.
Probably the most terrible thing that any of us could remind us of happening, happens to him.
And there's something about that in our life with God that he has.
And he's like, I'm in this terrible moment.
And I love the imagery of water, right?
Because he's saying, sorrow is hitting my life like the waves of the ocean.
Pain is hitting my life.
Loss.
Grief.
Heartbreak.
Disappointment.
Like, those things don't go away.
We live in this world.
Jesus said, I pray that you don't take them out of the world without you.
Keep them in the world, right?
Like, when we're alive, we're in the midst of that.
One thing that I used to in my congregation in BC is like, you know, one of the biggest points of tension in our life is that we don't get to skip our own lives.
And so much of a time, that's what we want.
I will have peace if I can get over it.
I will tell, I've been talking to a pastor in front of mine.
I said, I wish it could be next year.
Right?
And then I know where I'm working.
I know everything, where everything.
And like, it's a daily grind.
I just feel hard.
And I was like, I'm in the middle of this ocean, this storm coming over my last.
And then he said, but somehow in the middle of that, there's a river of peace coming through.
And what Jesus offers us, what Jesus invites us to is that if you give your life over to me, if you dwell with me,
if you pray when things are on, if you're thankful for what I have in you, if you meditate in me, if you dwell in me,
you can have peace that transcends all understanding, and that transcends all circumstances.
That's what I can feel.
I hear that.
I've been before you today, Andrew.
I don't know where everybody's in here, but a room beside somebody, many of us probably desperately needed.
And my prayer this morning that your spirit would come over and that peace like a river with that 10-hour wind would fall over us this morning,
that we would know that you love us and that we're safe in you.
And that the peace that transcends all understanding and all circumstances would come to pass.
In the name of your Son, Jesus, we pray.
Amen.